Charles D. Tuppen Erie County Stadium Papers
Buffalo History Museum. Research Library
Charles D. Tuppen Erie County Stadium Papers
1967 - 1989
Tuppen, Charles D.
The Buffalo History Museum 1 Museum Court Buffalo, NY 14216 Phone: 716-873-9644 ext. 306 Fax: 716-873-8754 Email: library@buffalohistory.org URI: http://www.buffalohistory.org
certificates; Erie County (N.Y.). Legislature; Stadiums New York (State) Erie County; Kenford Company; judicial records; plats (maps); site plans; speeches (documents)
Researchers wishing to access this collection must apply for a Scholar Pass and present valid photo ID upon arrival to the library.
Charles D. Tuppen was a lawyer with the Buffalo firm Falk, Siemer, Glick, Tuppen & Moloney. In November, 1967 he was elected as a Republican to the Erie County Legislature to represent the 11th District. As chairman of the Revenues and Assessments Committee, Tuppen was very active on the domed stadium issue. He favored a downtown (“Crossroads”) site for the stadium over the suburban Lancaster site, arguing that the downtown site would revitalize the City of Buffalo and prove more cost effective in the long run. In 1970, county legislators, unhappy with the size of bids made on the domed stadium at the Lancaster site, scrapped the project in favor of the open-air Rich Stadium in Orchard Park. Edward Cottrell and the Kenford Company, developers of the would-be domed stadium in Lancaster, sued Erie County for breach of contract. Litigation in the suit dragged on for some 18 years and resulted in the awarding of $10 million in damages to Cottrell and in long-term damage to Erie County’s credit rating.
The collection includes correspondence, reports, resolutions, contracts, notes, maps, cost estimates, and other financial data, architectural and engineering specifications, and speeches concerning plans for a domed stadium for Erie County, 1967- 1975; notes and printed materials about stadiums built in other U.S. cities; newspaper clippings; and records of Kenford Company et al. vs. the County of Erie, a suit in State Supreme Court regarding breach of the county’s stadium contract, 1971-1989.
Organized into ten series: I. Election certificate, 1967. II. Correspondence, 1967-1975. III. Reports, resolutions, notes, etc., ca. 1967-1971. IV. Cost estimates and other financial data, ca. 1967-1971. V. Speeches and statements by Tuppen, ca. 1967-1971. VI. Maps, n.d. VII. Architects' reports, portfolios, etc., ca. 1968-1971. VIII. Stadiums built in other cities, ca. 1968-1971. IX. Kenford Co. et al. vs. County of Erie, ca. 1971-1979. X. Newspaper clippings, 1968-1972. Correspondence and clippings arranged chronologically.
- Election Certificate, 1967
- General correspondence, 1967-1975
- Letters from constituents, 1968-1971
- Reports, resolutions, notes, etc., ca. 1967-1971
- Cost estimates and other financial data, ca. 1967-1971
- Speeches and statements by Tuppen, ca. 1967-1971
- Maps, undated
- Architect's reports, portfolios, etc., ca. 1968-1971
- Houston Astrodome
- Three Rivers Stadium, Pittsburgh
- Busch Stadium, St. Louis
- Other stadiums
- Kenford Company et al. vs. County of Erie, ca. 1971-1989
- Newspaper clippings, 1968-1972